Ruth Strout McCandless Collection on Nyogen Senzaki, 1895-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Publications., 1900-2006.
  - Subseries 3.1: Printed Material., 1931-1988.
    - Yasen Kanna: A Chat on a Boait in the Evening by Hakuin Zenji, translated by R.D.M. Shaw and Wilhelm Schiffer., 1957. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Zen Studies Society: Dharma Seasons Spring 1975, special issue for Dai Bosatsu Zendo Kon Go Ji. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: Dharma Seasons Fall 1975. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: Journal of The Zen Studies Society Spring/Summer 1986, issue no. 5. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: Journal of The Zen Studies Society Winter/Spring 1987, issue no. 6. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: Journal of The Zen Studies Society Summer/Fall 1987, issue no. 7. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: The Zen Studies Society Winter/Spring 1988, issue no. 8. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Zen Studies Society: New York Zendo pamphlet., after 1968. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Zen: A Method For Religious Awakening by Ruth Fuller Sasaki., 1959. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Zen: A Religion by Ruth Fuller Sasaki., 1958. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3.2: Monographs., 1900-2006.
    This subseries is comprised of a wide range of monographs on the study of Zen Buddhism, including works by seminal figures of the American Zen movement, such as Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki, Alan Watts, Soyen Shaku, and Robert Aitken. The texts include translations of ancient Buddhist writings, koans, sutras and sermons. Also included are Senzaki and McCandless' collaborative works, The Iron Flute (1964) and Buddhism and Zen (1953 & 1987). Translations in additional languages such as le Zen sagesse d'Extreme-Orient: un nouvel art de vivre? (1969), La Flauta de Hierro: Antologia de 100 Koans (2001), and 100 Koan Zen: ll flauto di ferro (2000) are also included.
    Subseries 3.2 is organized alphabetically by title.
    - 100 Koan Zen: ll Flauto di Ferro by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout McCandless., 2000. (Box 12)
    - A Buddhist Bible (Second Edition) by Dwight Goddard., 1938. (Box 10)
    - Buddha and the Gospel of Buddhism by Ananda K. Coomarasamy., 1964. (Box 10)
    - The Buddhism of Tibet or Lamaism by L.A. Waddell., 1958. (Box 10)
    - Buddhism and Zen by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout Mccandless., 1953. (Box 10)
    - Buddhism and Zen (Paperback, First Edition) by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout McCandless., 1953. (Box 12)
    - Buddhism and Zen (Paperback, Second Edition) by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout McCandless., 1987. (Box 12)
    - Creativity and Taoism by Chan Chung-yuan., 1963. (Box 11)
    - The Dhammapada by J.A.., 1945. (Box 10)
    - Dreams and Delights by L. Adams Beck., 1926. (Box 12)
    - The Embossed Tea Kettle by Hakuin Zenji., 1963. (Box 11)
    - Endless Vow: The Zen Path of Soen Nakagawa by Eido Tai Shimano, Kazuaki Tanahashi and Roko Sherry Chayat., 1988. (Box 12)
    - Essays in Zen Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1926. (Box 12)
    - Essays in Zen Buddhism (Second Series) by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1933. (Box 11)
    - The Essence of Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1947. (Box 12)
    - The Garden of Vision: A Story of Vision by L. Adams Beck., 1929. (Box 12)
    - Hinduism and Buddhism by Ananda K. Coomaraswamy., 1964. (Box 12)
    - History of Chinese Philosophy by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1914. (Box 12)
    - The House of Fulfilment by L. Adams Beck., 1927. (Box 12)
    - How the Swans Came to the Lake by Rick Fields., 1981. (Box 11)
    - An Introduction to Zen Buddhism by Daisetsu Teitaro Suzuki., 1934. (Box 12)
    - The Iron Flute (Paperback) by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout Mccandless., 2000. (Box 12)
    - The Iron Flute by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout McCandless., 1985. (Box 11)
    - The Key of Dreams by L. Adams Beck., 1934. (Box 12)
    - La Flauta de Hierro: Antologia de 100 Koans Zen by Nyogen Senzaki and Ruth Strout McCandless., 2001. (Box 12)
    - le Zen sagesse d'Extreme-Orient: un nouvel art de vivre? by Robert Linssen., 1969. (Box 10)
    - Living in the Light of Eternity by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1954. (Box 11)
    - Living by Zen by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1949. (Box 11)
    - The Lyrical Poems and Translations of Shelley by C.H. Herford., 1918. (Box 10)
    - Mahayana Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1948. (Box 10)
    - Manual of Zen Buddhism (reprint) by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1950. (Box 10)
    - Manual of Zen Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1985. (Box 11)
    - The Meaning of Life in Hinduism and Buddhism by Floyd H. Ross., 1952. (Box 10)
    - The Ninth Vibration and Other Stories by L. Adams Beck., 1933. (Box 12)
    - The Openers of The Gate by L. Adams Beck., 1930. (Box 12)
    - Original Dwelling Place by Robert Aitken., 1996. (Box 11)
    - Outlines of Mahayana Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1907. (Box 12)
    - Ruth Fuller Sasaki: Zen Pioneer by Isabel Stiring., 2006. (Box 10)
    - Sacred Books of the East., 1900. (Box 10)
      Includes selections from The Vedic Hymns, Zen-Avesta, Dhammapada, Upanishads, The Koran, and the Life of Buddha with critical and biographical sketches by Ephiphanuis Wilson, A.M.
    - Science and The Unseen World by Arthur Stanley Eddington., 1929. (Box 10)
    - Sermons of A Buddhist Abbot: Address on Religious Subjects by Soyen Shaku., 1906. (Box 10)
    - The Soen Roku: The Sayings and Doings of Master Soen by The Zen Studies Society., 1986. (Box 11)
    - The Sprint of Zen: A Way of Life, Work and Art in the Far East by Alan W. Watts., 1955. (Box 10)
    - Studies in Zen by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1955. (Box 12)
    - Taking the Path of Zen by Robert Aitken., 1982. (Box 11)
    - The Tibetan Book of The Dead or The After-Death Experiences on the Bardo Plane, according to Lama Kazi Dawa-Samdup's English Rendering by W.Y. Evans-Wentz., 1957. (Box 10)
    - The Training of the Zen Buddhist Monk by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1959. (Box 11)
    - The Two Sources of Morality and Religion by Henri Bergson., 1935. (Box 10)
    - The World of Zen by Nancy Wilson Ross., 1960. (Box 11)
    - The Zen Doctrine of No-Mind by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1949. (Box 12)
    - Zen in English Literature and Oriental Classics, by R.H. Blyth., 1948. (Box 12)
    - Zen Flesh, Zen Bones: A Collection of Zen and Pre-Zen Writing by Paul Reps., 1957. (Box 10)
    - Zen and Japanese Buddhism by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1958. (Box 12)
    - Zen and Japanese Culture by Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki., 1959. (Box 11)
    - Zen in the Martial Arts by Joe Hyams., 1982. (Box 10)
    - Zen for the West by Sohaku Ogata., 1959. (Box 11)
- Series 4: Personal Materials., circa 1896-1990s.
  This series includes personal photographs, clippings, correspondence, greeting cards, McCandless' datebook, a traditional Zen Buddhist Kesa robe, and a decorative scroll used in Senzaki's ministry. These materials document McCandless' connections and friendships with a range of figures in Zen Buddhist communities in the United States and Japan. The series contains photographs that document the 1955 trip Senzaki and McCandless took together to Japan, marking the first time Senzaki returned to Japan since he moved to California in 1905.
  Series 4 is organized into two subseries, which are subsequently organized alphabetically by subject title.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  - Subseries 4.1: Photographs., circa 1896-1984.
    This subseries contains photographic prints and negatives mostly comprised of McCandless' photographs from her travels to Japan. Portraits of McCandless and Senzaki are included, as well as images of Soen Nakagawa, Soyen Shaku and Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki. Other subject matter includes Takuhatsu, The Rinzai Buddhist temple Ryutakuji, artwork, and activities of Japanese monastery life such as cooking, zazen, and tea ceremonies.
    Subseries 4.1 is organized alphabetically by subject title.
    - Artwork and Landscape., circa 1940s-1980s. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Group and Individual Portraits., circa 1942-1984. (Box 13, Folders 2-3)
    - Monastery Images., 1955-1956. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Negatives., circa 1942-1971. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Negatives contain images of Japan, group portraits, and portraits of Nyogen Senzaki, including a photograph of Senzaki while he was incarcerated at the Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
    - Nyogen Senzaki., circa 1896-1958. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Includes an image of Senzaki while he was incarcerated at the Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
    - Photo Album., November 1958. (Box 18)
      Photo album containing images from Japan in 1958. Subjects include Soen Nakagawa, monasteries, and Yokohama harbor.
    - Ruth McCandless Japan Travels., 1955-1956. (Box 14, Folders 1-2, Box 13, Folder 7)
      Box 13, Folder 7 contains negatives from this series of images.
    - Soen Nakagawa., 1951-1964. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.2: Correspondence and Memorabilia., circa 1930s-1990s.
    This subseries contains correspondence, artwork, clippings, pamphlets, McCandless's datebook, a traditional Zen Buddhist Kesa robe, and a decorative scroll used in Senzaki's ministry. Highlights include Senzaki's obituary, a program for Koyasan Betsuin's memorial service, and correspondence from Senzaki, including letters sent during his incarceration at the Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
    Subseries 4.2 is organized alphabetically by subject title.
    - Artwork., circa 1940s-1960s. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Clippings and Pamphlets., circa 1940s-1990s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence., circa 1937-1980s.; These files contain organic material. Use caution while handling. (Box 14, Folders 6-7, Box 15, Folders 1-3)
      Contains personal letters with the Zen Studies Society and Nyogen Senzaki, including correspondence during his incarceration at Heart Mountain, and hand painted leaves sent to McCandless.
    - Datebook., 1955-1956. (Box 18)
    - Decorative Scroll., undated. (Box 17)
      Scroll of Kannon Bodhisattva used by Nyogen Senzaki in his ministry.
    - Nyogen Senzaki's Robe., circa 1930-1950. (Box 16)
      Traditional set of Buddhist Kesa robes used by Nyogen Senzaki
    - Personal Ephemera., circa 1950s-1980s. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Contains handwritten notes, travel itineraries and writings.
    - Record., After 1946. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      One record containing classical Japanese music distributed by Nippon Colombia Co., Ltd.